<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>slu-seek-learn-use</title>
    <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use" />
    <updated>2018-03-28T04:04:22+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>abhishek rai</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to add widgets in a single page on a Wordpress site?</title>
        <author>
            <name>abhishek rai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/adding-widgets-in-a-single-page-on-a-wordpress-site.html"/>
        <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/adding-widgets-in-a-single-page-on-a-wordpress-site.html</id>
            <category term="wordpressdevelopment"/>
            <category term="wordpress"/>

        <updated>2018-03-27T08:49:49+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/media/posts/2/pexels-photo-261662.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>A few days back while working on a <a href="https://wordpress.org/" title="Wordpress Org">Wordpress</a> site, I had to integrate a <a href="https://elasticemail.com/integrations/elastic-email-subscribe-form/" title="Elastic Email Wordpress Widget Link">widget</a> on a single page.</p>
<p>I know only a couple of tits and bots of the current Wordpress platform since there are so many plugins ow for each job and every developer has her own favourites one. So, if you are working on a repair&amp;maintenance job of an existing website, the first and biggest hurdle is to orient yourself with the way the site has been built, and the plugins which has been used.</p>
<p>I did some queries on search engines and found out that one way to incorporate a widget on a single page, is through use of <a href="https://codex.wordpress.org/shortcode" title="Wordpress Shortcodes">shortcodes</a>.</p>
<p>Well that's good, but then how to generate a shortcode for the widget which I had to install?</p>
<p>One more query and after watching a couple of videos and reading articles, I found <a href="https://webdesign.anmari.com/1649/shortcode-any-widget/" title="Anmari.com's Shortcode Any Widget plugin">Shortcode Any Widget</a> plugin, which when installed generates shortcodes for any widget.</p>
<p>At that point of time I did not research a lot on other such similar plugins available, and the whole idea was to test the utility of this one and then proceed.</p>
<p>This widget was  easy to use and did not require much to do, once installed and I had my shortcode for the widget.</p>
<p>Now, the problem was how to use this widget in the page itself. The page was built with <a href="https://wpbakery.com/" title="WPBakery Page Builder">WPBakery Page Builder</a>. I tried adding element via the page builder's editor, but then I could not see my widget. I thought that once, I have added the widget and generated a shortcode, the element to be used in the page would be automatically added. But it was not there.</p>
<p>I had to get my element of WP Bakery, via the shortcode generated of the widget I wanted to use on the page. So, it definitely had to be resolved via some kind of settings on the WP Bakery console. After all, Wordpress would be having so many other widgets and elements to be used.</p>
<p>I looked at the WPBakery console in the dashboard and there it was the link to the <a href="https://kb.wpbakery.com/docs/learning-more/shortcode-mapper/" title="WPBakery Shortcode Mapper">Shortcode Mapper</a> and then after a couple of tries, I was able to generate an element via the shortcode mapper.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>About this site</title>
        <author>
            <name>abhishek rai</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/about-this-site.html"/>
        <id>https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/about-this-site.html</id>

        <updated>2018-03-27T08:49:35+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/media/posts/1/open-book-library-education-read-159621.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p><img class="post__image--wide" src="file://https://therealmccoy.github.io/seek-learn-use/media/posts/1//open-book-library-education-read-159621.jpeg" alt="abhishek rai's learnings" width="1280" height="961">What you learn; is a useful information, knowledge or skill.</p>
<p>During the course of my day to day activities, I encounter some stuff, which is a new learning. This site details all these stuff.</p>
<p>A couple of reasons for doing that:</p>
<p class="align-left">a.) That I have a list and could gauge my progress b.) I could reference the list and revise my knowledge on the subject c.) I could reference the list and then update my knowledge on those subjects.</p>
<p>Please be rest assured that this would cover a wide range of topics and subjects and may vary from season to season, depending upon what I am doing.</p>
<p>A couple of months back, it could have been a lot about fishing, when I was apprenticing.</p>
<p>I wish I could give you a list of topics, but you could find out from the tags itself.</p>
<p>Please feel free to comment and reach out to me, if you have any query or comments.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
